原创翻译  双语字幕
最新连载海外影视剧下载
请登陆 www.YYeTs.com
仅供交流学习  禁止商用盈利
《沼泽怪物》前情回顾
Previously on Swamp Thing...
你离开家有多久了
How long has it been since you were home?
我是艾比·亚凯恩医生
My name is Dr. Abby Arcane,
是疾控中心流行病情报部门的
with the CDC's Epidemic Intelligence Service.
艾比·亚凯恩
Abby Arcane!
莉兹
Liz.
你最近有在码头注意到任何不寻常的事情吗
Have you seen anything unusual at the docks lately?
我听到消息  有人雇船
I have heard whispers of someone hiring boats
晚上进入沼泽深处
to go out into the swamp at night.
不好意思  你到底是谁
Excuse me? Who are you exactly?
你迟早会有话想问我的
You're gonna wanna speak to me sooner or later.
马特  你现在是警察了
Matt? You're a cop now.
科尔先生
Mr. Coyle?
我们已经控制住局面了  没事的
We have it under control. It's okay.
但是什么都不管用  不是吗
Well, nothing's working, is it?
-你是谁来着  -霍兰
- Who are you, again? - Holland.
这个地方有特别之处
There's something special about this place,
我们都心知肚明
we all know that.
在这里生活得够久
You live here long enough,
就能从骨子里感受到其特别之处
you feel it in your bones.
这是个样本
This is a sample.
上面这层透明的  只是沼泽水  对吧
This clear shit on top, that's just swamp water, right?
但是底部这些  看到了吗
But right there on the bottom, you see that?
这些不应该出现
That doesn't belong.
肯定是某种生物促进剂之类的东西
It's gotta be some sort of biological accelerant.
但是它只会增强诱变剂
But it only jacks up mutagens.
爸爸
Daddy!
你想喝杯酒吗
May I offer you a drink?
我绝对需要喝一杯
I sure as hell could use one.
我们有两个共同点了
That's two things we have in common.
箱子里的东西是某种生物促进剂
The stuff in the box, it's a biological accelerant.
跟我们从沼泽里提取到的很像
It's like the stuff we pulled from the swamp.
所以是有人倒在这里的吗
So someone's dumping it here?
需要我帮你吗
Can I help you?
亚历克
Alec!
Alec?
艾比  你绕了个圈
Abby, you circled round.
这地方你检查过两遍了
Been through this area twice.
我们不能停下  马特
We can't stop, Matt.
-他可能还活着  -可能吗
- He could still be alive. - Could he?
你说整艘船起火爆炸了
You said the entire boat went up in flames,
看起来确实是那么回事
and it sure looks like that's what happened.
警长来了
Sheriff's here.
找到遗骸了吗
Found any remains?
大概找不出什么  整艘船爆炸了
We probably won't find much. The whole thing went up.
原因呢
Reason?
也许是引擎的火花点燃了油箱
Maybe a spark from the engine ignited the fuel tank.
等等  你认为这是意外事故
Wait, you think this was an accident?
艾比
Abby.
你把头发留长了
You let your hair grow.
你应该知道  亚历克·霍兰正在调查
You should know that Alec Holland was investigating
发生在这片沼泽的非法倾倒
illegal dumping on this swamp,
他认为倾倒可能与当前的疫情有关...
dumping he thought might be related to this current outbreak--
而你应该知道
And you should know,
如果说在这里当警长让我学会了什么
if I've learned one thing from being sheriff here,
那就是这片沼泽里总是发生可怕的事
there's all kinds of awful that happens in this swamp.
不过我觉得这点你比任何人都清楚
But I think you know that. Better than anyone.
兰德瑞
Landry!
-兰德瑞  -什么事  老大
- Landry! - Yeah, boss?
从岸边开始逆流而上搜寻
Start down the shore and work your way back up.
明白
Copy that.
到对面后联系  靠边搜寻
Call from the other side, contour sweep.
等等  听着  你得警告你的手下
Wait. Wait. Listen, you have to warn your people.
我在沼泽里看到了什么
I saw something out there on the water.
是个很大的生物
It was something big.
艾比  我们这边经常收到野猪出没的报警
Abby, we get reports of boar in the area all the time.
那不是野猪
It was not a boar.
-那是个人  是...  -别这样
- It was a man. It was... - Come on...
长得像个人
It was like a man.
当时很暗
It was dark.
你因为爆炸受了刺激
You were keyed up from the explosion.
她可能是  她可能看到了用两条腿站着的动物
Now, she could have... She could've seen something on two legs.
我也不知道  一头熊
I don't know... A bear.
是啊  也许是一头从加拿大走过来的灰熊
Yeah, maybe a grizzly wandered all the way down from Canada
史上头一遭
for the first time ever.
亚凯恩医生  回家去
Dr. Arcane, go home.
兰德瑞  告诉你的人  小心熊出没
Landry, tell your people to be on alert for a possible bear.
熊  在沼泽里
Bear? In this swamp?
随你便吧  警长
Whatever you say, Sheriff.
翻译  布塔一生黑华纳
翻译  DustD
翻译  冰岛豆腐
翻译  Husky
翻译  盆栽
翻译  Serrino
翻译  Sakura的小书包
翻译  余欢
翻译  马丁马丁回音山
翻译  iLOST
翻译  小酸奶
时间轴  紫夏
时间轴  西·查
校对  布塔请愿HBO
后期  渔夫
字幕总监制  布塔爱不动DC
沼泽   怪物
第一季  第二集
我还以为我清楚
You know, I thought I knew what
回玛雷要面对什么  但是...
I was getting into coming back to Marais, but...
这地方对你一直很不友好
This place wasn't very easy for you.
即便是在好日子里
Even on the best of days.
是啊
Yeah.
总之  感谢你让我住下来
Anyway... Thanks for letting me stay.
不是这里就是12号公路上的"住多多"旅馆了
Well, when it's this or the Bide-A-Wee Motel on Route 12...
他们肯定不会拿出波本威士忌等你的
But they wouldn't have a shot of bourbon waiting for you.
我们有两个共同点了
Two things we have in common.
什么
What?
没什么
Nothing.
那么  你知道了
So, you heard.
关于你一晚上的经历吗  是的
About the night you had? Oh, yeah.
我喜欢开着警讯监控仪睡觉
I like to fall asleep listening to the police scanner.
很让人宽心
It's soothing.
我和霍兰不熟  但他看起来...
I barely knew Holland, but he seemed like...
是个好人
Good guy.
我真挺喜欢他的  莉兹
I really liked him, Liz.
苏西  亲爱的  我是爱德华兹医生
Susie, honey, it's Dr. Edwards.
听说你做了个噩梦
Heard you had a bad nightmare.
那不是噩梦
It wasn't a nightmare.
他在伤害自己
He was hurting himself.
他不明白自己身上发生了什么
He doesn't understand what's happening to him.
我不明白  谁受伤了
I don't understand. Who's being hurt?
黑暗中的男人
The man in the dark.
他很害怕
He's so scared.
我得去找他
I need to go to him.
好了  亲爱的  那只是场梦
Okay, honey, it was just a dream.
你现在需要休息  好吗
You need to get your rest now, okay?
玛丽亚
Maria?
Maria!
玛丽亚
Maria?
肖娜还小的时候
When Shawna was a little girl...
有时我会躺在她身边
Sometimes I would lay down next to her
只是想听着她呼吸
just to listen to her breathe.
别这样对你自己
Don't do this to yourself.
你总是不在家  埃弗里
You weren't around, Avery.
你没有我那么了解她
You didn't know her like I did.
我也失去了肖娜
I lost Shawna, too.
艾比
Abby!
靠
Shit.
哈伦
Harlan.
你听起来精神抖擞
Well, you sound alert and rested.
怎么了  有什么变化吗
What's up? Any changes?
苏西·科尔晚上病情发作了一次
Susie Coyle had an episode during the night.
她的心率和血压飙升
Her heart rate and BP jumped,
但我们在处理了
but we're on it.
好  我了解你  哈伦
Okay, I know you, Harlan,
一次说完吧
drop the other shoe.
出现两个新病例
We've got two new cases.
他们的用药方案是一样的  但是
They're on the same drug regimen, but...
目前为止  他们病情稳定
So far, they're stable.
该死
Shit.
这个病没完没了
This thing isn't stopping.
莉兹  我在想
Liz, I was thinking,
-我不确定  -你自便
- and I'm not sure-- - Wow. Help yourself.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
你一定是艾比吧  我是玛歌
You must be Abby. Margaux.
-你好  -早
- Hi. - Morning.
我煮的咖啡都超级浓
When I make the coffee, it's nuclear strong.
莉茲往咖啡豆上倒点水
Liz spills some water over a few beans
就觉得那是意式浓缩咖啡
and thinks she has an espresso.
你跟我朋友说我坏话
You trashing me to my friends?
趁捕虾船还没开走快上船吧
Now run before that shrimp boat leaves without you.
小心  她早上脾气不太好
Watch out. She's grumpy in the morning.
怎么  你也从不跟我说你的男友们
What? It's not like you tell me about your boyfriends.
睡得怎么样
So, how'd you sleep?
你觉得亚历克的船爆炸是意外吗
Do you think Alec's boat blowing up was an accident?
看来是没睡好
Not well, then.
好吧
Fine.
我觉得时间点很蹊跷
I don't like the timing.
我又是个悲观多疑的记者
And I'm a cynical and suspicious reporter.
嗯  我的问题是
Yeah. Here's my problem.
亚历克不仅仅是在调查非法倾倒
Alec wasn't just looking into illegal dumping,
他还在追踪这个病的发展
he was tracking the progress of the disease.
他觉得他有所发现
And he thought that he was onto something.
现在他死了  你没法问他
And now he's gone, and you can't ask him.
嗯
Yeah.
今天出现了两个新病例  所以
Well, two new cases came in today, so...
我们现在的方法并不奏效
Whatever we're doing, it's not working.
我觉得我得去他的实验室  看看他的工作成果
I think I need to get into his lab and look through his work.
但是今天那里全是警察
Except the cops are all over it today.
警讯监控仪  记得吗
Police scanner, remember?
就连玛雷的警察也是有规章制度的
Even Marais' finest have protocol.
这是暴力死亡案件的标准
It's standard in the case of violent death.
雇用亚历克的人也许能给我权限
The man who hired Alec could give me access.
你不会是想去找埃弗里吧
Are you seriously talking about going to Avery?
在他们那样对你之后
After what they did to you?
妹子  别让他扰乱你的心智
Girl, do not let that man mess with your mind.
她煮的咖啡确实不错
She does make good coffee.
别换话题
Don't change the subject.
埃弗里·桑德兰是操纵大师
Avery Sunderland is a master manipulator.
你第一次就伤得够重了
Okay, you got hurt enough the first time around.
-我不会有事的  -艾比
- I'm gonna be fine. - Abby...
回头见
See you later.
请进
Come in.
这边请
Right this way.
爸爸我爱你
你和肖娜以前总在这里拆圣诞礼物
I don't think we've had a fire in that thing since you and Shawna
但我们再也没点燃过这个壁炉
used to open your Christmas presents in here.
没有孩子的房子总是摆脱不掉他们的回声
A house without children never loses the echoes, you know.
看你都长多大了
Look at you.
不敢相信已经过了十四年
I can't believe it's been 14 years!
-你好  艾比  -你好
- Hey, Abby. - Hey.
来  给你倒点喝的
Come on, let's get you something to drink.
想吃东西吗  饿不饿
You want something to eat? You hungry?
不了  其实我是来办公事的
No, I'm actually here in my professional capacity.
我知道  在疾控中心工作
I know. With the CDC.
医学博士  传染病
Medical doctor, infectious diseases,
专家  太厉害了
specialist, that's impressive.
我们刚认识你的时候
From the time we took you in,
你才八岁  聪明伶俐
eight-years-old and bright as a whip,
我就知道你会是做大事的人
I knew that you would do great things.
-埃弗里...  -听着  在我们继续之前
- Avery... - Hey, listen, before we go any further,
请你
please just...
先坐一会  艾比  拜托了
Sit down for a minute, Abby, please.
我想和你谈谈
I wanna talk to you.
好
Okay.
我欠你一个道歉
I owe you an apology.
和玛丽亚不同
I never blamed you for Shawna's death
肖娜的死我从没怪过你  我早该说清楚的
the way that Maria did, and I should have made that clear.
我真希望当时我能鼓起勇气
And I wish to hell now that I would have stepped up.
你承受了她所有的愤怒
You bore the full brunt of her hostility,
你逃离了这里  我不怪你
and I do not blame you for getting out of Dodge.
我明白她当时很伤心
I understood that she was upset.
她当时濒临崩溃
She was hanging by a thread,
刚刚经历丧女之痛
and I couldn't bear the thought of fighting with her
一想到要跟她争吵我就承受不住  但是
when the pain was so fresh, but...
有这么长的时间让我思考  艾比
I've had a long time to think, Abby.
你当时是个17岁的孩子
You were a 17-year-old kid.
我本该处理的更好的
I should've done better.
那样的话  也许我就不会
Maybe if I had, I wouldn't have...
同时失去我的两个女儿了  是吧
Wouldn't have lost both my daughters, huh?
玛丽亚还好吗
Is Maria all right?
我们会挺过去的
We'll get through it.
是因为我
It's because of me.
因为我回来了  我挑起了这些情绪
It's me coming back, I stirred up all this emotion.
我
I...
对不起
I'm sorry.
告诉我疾控中心需要我做什么吧  艾比
Why don't you tell me what I can do for the CDC, Abby?
是这样
Well...
你曾有个雇员  亚力克·霍兰
You had an employee, Alec Holland.
天哪  对  亚力克
Jesus. Yes, Alec.
警长今早刚通知了我
Sheriff just filled me in this morning.
我不清楚是怎么回事  到现在都不敢相信
I don't know what happened. I still can't even believe it.
我认为他曾进行过
Well, I believe that he had
能帮我们治愈这种疾病的研究
some research that could help us cure this disease.
还有
And...
我需要进他的实验室
I need to get into his lab.
我明白了
I see.
我猜你来找我
And I imagine you came to me
是因为露西莉亚的副手把实验室封锁了
because Lucilia's deputies have got it locked down?
是的
Yes.
但只要你打个电话  一切就都解决了
But one call from you, and that would all go away.
实验室里到处都是我的律师所说的
That lab is full of what my lawyers call...
"专有信息"
"Proprietary information."
好吧  但很多人正命悬一线
Okay. But people's lives are at risk.
没错
Yes.
如果我觉得实验室里有任何
And if I thought there was anything in there
可能帮到你的信息
that might help you,
我就会主动交出钥匙
I'd be the first to hand over the key.
但我在那项研究上投入了一大笔钱
But I've invested a small fortune in that research,
一旦我打开大门
and once I open up that barn door,
开弓可就没有回头箭了
there's no getting the horses back inside.
那些数据不知会落到谁手上
That data could wind up anywhere.
我可以申请法院指令
I could get a court order.
如果迫不得已
If I have to.
当然了  到那时
But, of course, by then,
所有的专有信息可能已经消失了
all that proprietary information might be gone.
可能吧
It might be.
但更重要的是
But here's what's more important,
无论发生什么  我还是爱你的
regardless of what happens, I'll still love you.
永远欢迎你来我家
And you will always be welcome in this house.
你总是有本事
You know, you always had
让"拒绝"听起来像是送人情
a way of making a "No" sound like a favor.
戴尔瑞餐馆
你知道我为什么来
You know why I'm here.
拜托了  我需要你的帮助
Please. I need your help.
我本以为我已经控制住了
I thought I had it under control.
这份痛苦在侵蚀我
This pain, gnawing at me.
但是怎么可能忘记失去独子的痛苦呢
But how can anyone forget the loss of their only child?
忘不掉的  玛丽亚
You don't, Maria.
你要想办法慢慢放下
You find a way to let it rest.
我做不到
I can't.
就仿佛...
It's like...
我又能听到她说话了
I can hear her again.
她...
She's...
她在呼唤我
She's calling out to me.
好吧
Fine.
好吧  坐下
Fine, sit.
我要你回忆肖娜
I want you to think about Shawna.
你对她的感觉
How you felt about her.
她那时的死状
How she died.
她现在的灵魂
And her spirit now.
现在
Now...
展现出来吧
Show me.
妮缪
Nimue...
玛丽亚
Maria?
怎么回事
What... What happened?
光明与黑暗间的平衡发生了变化
There's been a shift in the balance of the light and the dark.
-肖娜是不是...  -那里有怪物
- Is Shawna-- - Something's out there.
我触碰了它
I touched it.
它巨大  黑暗
Something vast, dark, and
生长在可怕的腐水中
growing in the awful and the rot of the water.
如果你像你说的那样相信我
If you trust me like you say you do...
你就该放手
You'll let this go.
-我做不到  -肖娜已经死了
- I can't. - Shawna's dead.
不
No.
让她安息
Let her rest.
让她走吧
Let her go.
天哪
Oh, my God.
亚历克就住在这地方
This is where Alec was staying?
看来他也不喜欢"住多多"旅馆
Guess he didn't like the Bide-A-Wee, either.
蓝魔鬼影碟出租店
卡西迪把后面的房间租出去了
Cassidy rents out rooms in the back.
但愿霍兰会把工作带回家
Let's just hope Holland brought work home with him.
影像出租
-等下  -丹尼
- Wait! - Danny?
在我开始领取社保之前
Before I have to start collecting social security.
在吗
Hello?
有人吗
-女士们  -没出事吧
- Hi, ladies. - Everything okay?
没事  抱歉  我只是在为试镜排练
Yeah. I'm sorry, I was just rehearsing for an audition.
你是个演员
You're an actor?
是啊
Well, yeah.
蓝魔鬼
烂番茄上新鲜度83%
83% on Rotten Tomatoes.
他们喜欢我自己做特技
They like that I do my own stunts.
艾比  这是丹尼尔·卡西迪
Abby, this is Daniel Cassidy.
业主和经营人
Owner and operator,
更不用说  他还是常驻玛雷的电影明星
not to mention, Marais' resident movie star.
谢谢  这个地方对我来说只是个小配菜
Thanks. This place is just a little side dish for me.
刮目相看
I'm impressed.
那样的话  我有一张电影海报给你
Well, in that case, I have a movie poster for you.
很乐意为你签名
I'd be happy to sign it.
丹尼  我朋友在疾控中心工作
Danny, my friend works for the CDC...
艾比·亚凯恩医生
Dr. Abby Arcane.
我们是为亚历克·霍兰来的
We're here about Alec Holland.
那家伙的事真让人难过
So sad to hear about that guy.
嗯  我能不能看看他的房间
Yeah, I was hoping I could take a look inside of his room.
当然  没问题  但你什么也找不到
Well, yeah, sure, but you're not gonna find anything.
-为什么  -警察一小时前来过
- Why? - The cops were here an hour ago.
待了二十分钟
In and out in 20 minutes.
他有电脑吗  任何东西
Did he have a computer? Anything?
他有  但他被解雇的时候  电脑被收回了
Yeah, he did, but they took it back from him when he got fired.
他自己买不起
Couldn't afford his own.
见鬼  他就经常用我的电脑
Well, hell, half the time he would use mine
编辑他的日志  然后上传
to edit his journal entries before he would upload them.
他有工作日志
He had a work journal?
不  不是工作的  好吧  也许算是吧
No, not work. Well, it may be work.
大部分都是沼泽泥潭之类的东西
Mostly just mud-whomping-in-the-swamp kinda stuff.
他是那种喜欢花鸟鱼虫的怪人
He was the kinda guy that dug plants and birds and shit.
狼人  你好
Garou, hi!
嗯  警察把他放这儿了
Yeah, the cops dropped him off here.
他们不知道要怎么安置他
They didn't know what else to do with him.
对不起  伙计  他不会回来了
I'm sorry, buddy. He's not coming back.
有没有地方能让我看下这个
Is there a place I could take a look at this?
当然
Yeah, sure.
不如来楼上找个座位  我给你看
You know what? Come grab a seat upstairs. I'mma show ya.
丹尼  上周日你怎么了
So, Danny, what happened to you on Sunday?
餐馆的即兴演奏会你缺席了
We missed you at Roadhouse Jam.
请随意
Help yourself.
不用在意上周日
Never mind what happened on Sunday.
你要期待的是下周日
It's next Sunday that you need to get excited about.
-是吗  -我正在制作混音
- Oh, yeah? - I am mixing tracks together
那效果别人想都想不到
that no one has ever even conceived of.
就像放入红辣椒卡津酱  一起搅拌
Throw in cayenne cajun sauce, mixing all that up too.
蓝魔鬼
今天这条日志很带劲  我刚被解雇
Well, I got a very exciting entry today. I just got fired.
真是太棒了
So that's awesome.
那我为什么还要来沼泽里呢
So why am I still in the middle of the swamp?
可能因为我是受虐狂吧
Masochist, maybe.
也可能是因为我有所发现
Or because I know I'm on to something.
我知道  我只是...
I know it. I just...
需要一点时间来证明罢了  但愿快了
need some time to prove it is all, and hopefully soon.
因为我最讨厌被解雇
Because there's nothing I hate more than being fired,
以及一贫如洗
than being poor.
而且我需要买新凉鞋
And I need new sandals.
好了  先说坏消息
All right, bad news first is
我们现在知道有人一直在
we now know that somebody has been dumping
往沼泽里倒促进剂
accelerant out in the swamp.
我们尚不清楚原因  但好消息是
Why is still a fucking mystery to us, but, uh, good news is,
我们认为如果找到并回收所有的箱子
is we think that if we, uh, find and collect all these boxes,
也许可以阻止这件事  所以
we may be able to, uh, stop this thing, so...
我们
We, um...
"我们"  是吧  老天  今天都忙糊涂了
"We," right? Jesus, it's been a long day.
我今天一直在和疾控中心派来的一位医生合作
Yeah, I've been working with a, uh, doctor from the CDC today,
艾比·亚凯恩  她...
Abby Arcane. She's, um...
她很聪明  非常聪明  很有干劲
She's very smart, very smart. Very driven, and, uh...
她谷歌搜索我了
Well, she googled me, so.
她很可爱
She's quite lovely.
到了到了
Oh, here we go, here we go.
找到了  好了
Got something, got something... All right.
艾比
Abby?
-你没事吧  -嗯
- You good? - Yeah.
哈伦
苏西·科尔不在病房
找不到她  打给我
该死
Shit.
-苏西的事  -她还好吗
- Susie. - Is she all right?
她失踪了
She's missing.
你知道安排了谁来接手我的学生吗
Have you heard anything more about who's taking my students?
知道  齐默曼教授同意在我们回去之前
Yes, Professor Zimmerman has agreed to cover your classes
帮你代课
until we get back.
齐默曼  他就是个什么都不懂的庸人
Zimmerman? The man is mediocrity wrapped in ignorance.
我们见埃弗里·桑德兰时你不会这么说他吧
You're not gonna do that when we meet Avery Sunderland, right?
当然不会
No, of course not.
因为他不需要你跟他说
Because he does not need to be told
他束缚了你的创造力
he's a dead weight on your creativity
而且除了有钱一无是处
and only useful for his money.
或是你当场产生的任何
Or whatever opinion you happen to form on the spot
-想要分享的观点  -嗯
- and need to share. - Yeah.
真话能节约时间
Truth saves time.
-他送来了你喜欢的诱变剂  -我知道
- He sent you those mutagens that you love. - I know.
-他还付了很多钱让你研制促进剂  -对
- And he's paid a lot of money for you to develop the accelerant. - Yes.
然后他打断了我的工作  跟我说
And then he interrupted my work by telling me,
"快滚过来  有紧急情况"
"Hey, get your ass down here, there's an emergency."
我等不及要看是什么病了
I can't wait to see what this disease of his is.
大概是投放促进剂的人感冒了
You know, probably someone dispersing the accelerant caught a cold.
我们是伍德罗夫妇
We're the Woodrues.
我们是来见...
We're here to see Mr...
是的  桑德兰先生告诉我他要见你
Yes, Mr. Sunderland told me to expect you.
请你绕到沼泽那边
If you could go around to the marsh side.
他在练习挥杆
He's working on his swing.
挥杆
His swing?
我没那个打算
I'm not going to.
我只是觉得没必要去得罪
I'm just saying that there's no point in offending the man
那个给你科研经费的人
who's funding your research.
我没想去得罪他  好吗
I have no intention of offending him, okay?
即使最后发现他是个自大的蠢货
Even if he ends up being an entitled idiot,
就像齐默曼一样
like Zimmerman.
在这边
Over here!
我们被召唤了
We're being summoned.
-杰森  -你看那棵树
- Jason. - Look at that tree.
杰森  别停下
Jason, keep walking.
-杰森  -不...
- Jason. - No...
-你好吗  -挺好的
- How are you? - Good.
你是这里的园丁吗
Are you the gardener?
这是一棵日本榆
This is a Japanese elm,
并且处于移植休克
and it's in transplant shock.
快去厨房
Go up to the kitchen,
盛一碗糖水
get a pan of water and sugar.
然后你得像这样照料这里的根须
And then you're gonna treat the roots right here like this.
好吗  明白了吗
Okay? You got that?
-是的  -去吧
- Yes, sir. - Go.
他在干什么
What is he doing?
欣赏你的树
Admiring your trees.
他喜欢树
He likes trees?
我是杰森·伍德罗博士
Dr. Jason Woodrue.
非常感谢你的邀请
Thank you for asking us here.
这里真漂亮
It's very beautiful.
是的  我们对此十分自豪
Yes, we're very proud of it.
900英亩[3.6平方公里]
900 acres.
我的员工会非常乐意向你展示
I know my staff would be happy to show you
更多的园艺  伍德罗夫人
more of the gardens, Mrs. Woodrue.
她也是伍德罗博士  所以
Yeah, she's also Dr. Woodrue, so, um...
我们一起谈
She stays.
好吧
That's fine.
那么杰森  你在搞什么鬼
So what the fuck, Jason?
不好意思  你说什么
I beg your pardon?
你跟我说你的促进剂会让植物长得更快
You told me your accelerant would make things grow faster.
更多的树排干沼泽里的水
More trees to drain the water,
露出更多的土地用来开发
more land to develop,
更多的植物用来研发药物
more plants to develop into drugs
和化妆品  以及各种可以盈利的东西
and cosmetics and things to monetize.
促进剂成功了
The accelerant works.
是成功了
Oh, it works!
太他妈成功了
Like a son of a bitch.
我们还多了满满一医院的病人
But we've also got a hospital full up with people
全都患上了某种吓人的绿色流感
with some kind of crazy green flu.
那个病不可能是我的促进剂导致的
There's no way that my accelerant was responsible for that.
促进剂倒进水里  然后人们生病了
The accelerant dumped in the water, and people getting sick?
别想糊弄我  博士大人
Don't talk down to me, Mr. Doctor.
源自沼泽的疾病不是什么新鲜事
Diseases emerge from swamps all of the time.
登革热  埃博拉  疟疾
Dengue fever, ebola, malaria.
以沼泽为生
Living on a swamp
就跟生活在花样百出的粪坑旁一样
is like living next to a gloriously diverse cesspool.
但我会...我会去调查
But I'm gonna... I'm gonna look into it.
不  你要解决问题
No, you're gonna fix it.
因为疾控中心来人了  还跟大家说
Because the CDC's in town, telling people
这次的疾病是他们以前从未见过的
that this disease is like nothing they've ever seen before.
我正在处理我这边的事情
Now I'm taking care of things on my end.
但如果这个促进剂的烂摊子牵连到我
But if my name gets linked with this accelerant mess,
就会有人被起诉
there's gonna be lawsuits,
就会有人被逮捕
there's gonna be arrests.
好人会有怎样的下场
Things are going to happen to nice people,
你完全无法想象
like you've never even dreamed of.
而我会确保  我们三个人
And I'm gonna make sure that they happen
是一条船上的蚂蚱  博士们
to all three of us, doctors.
她是怎么失踪的
So how did she go missing?
她翻窗出去了
She got out her window.
但我不知道她是怎么做到的
But I don't know how she managed it.
她有传染性吗
Is she contagious?
我们得假设如此
We have to assume it.
我们还得假设
We also have to assume
她的病情会急转直下
that her condition is going to worsen, and fast.
与此同时  再过半小时天就要黑了
Meanwhile, we've got another half-hour of daylight.
最多半小时
If that.
我是凯博
Cable.
好  我们这就来
Right, we're on it.
南码头有发现
Found something down at the South docks.
-我是亚凯恩医生  -我是康尼尔
- Dr. Arcane. - Conyer.
我觉得有个生病的孩子来过这里
I think a sick kid was here.
在栏杆上找到的  她一定是用钉子割断的
Found it on the railing. She must have ripped it on a nail.
蒙特里维尔行政区
治安官
船舶变电站
这个船位是谁的
Who docks here?
大部分时间是狩猎监督员的
The Game Warden, mostly.
维恩·罗比泰尔
Vern Robitelle.
他几分钟前刚把船开出去
He took a boat out just a few minutes ago.
你知道他要去哪里吗
You know where he's headed?
他提到了蚊子湾
Said something about Skeeter Cove.
蚊子湾
Skeeter Cove?
我们就是在那里找到了苏西爸爸的船
That's where we found Susie's father's boat.
她要进沼泽
She's gone into the swamp.
所有人员注意  苏西·科尔从玛雷总医院走失
All officers, Susie Coyle's gone missing from Marais General.
她九岁...
She's nine-years-old--
这里是罗比泰尔  6号监督员
Robitelle, game 6.
总部  我看到
Base, I'm seeing some, uh,
蚊子湾的水面上有灯光
lights on the water off the cove out here.
收到  罗比  你需要支援吗
Copy that, Robi. You want backup?
不用  可能就是些老家伙违规捕鳄鱼
Nah, it's probably just some old boys over the limit on gator.
我靠近一点  看看情况
I'm gonna get closer, see what I can see.
收到
Copy that.
你们在干什么
What are you doing?
狩猎监督员  船上的人  东西放下
Game Warden. You on the boat, pencils down.
快点
Right now.
罗比  是你吗
Hey, Robi, is that you?
妈的  朗德罗  又是你
Oh, shit, Landreaux. Again?
是啊
Yeah.
我对天发誓  我们正准备回去
Hey, I swear to God, we're just about to head in.
是是是  我知道
Yeah, yeah, yeah, I know, I know.
你清楚得很  我必须得检查一番  兄弟
And you know more than most I gotta check you out, brother.
来吧
Come on.
该死  冷静  该死
Shit. Be cool. Shit.
我去
Well, shit.
箱子里是什么
What's in the box?
快点  朗德罗  我想简单快速地...
Come on, Landreaux, I wanna make this as quick and as painless...
该死  操  你干什么  伙计
Shit! Fuck! What are you doing, man?
这是罗比啊  你在干什么
This is Robi! What are you doing?
你干了什么
What'd you do, man?
这混蛋不该管闲事
Piece of shit should have backed off.
完蛋了  伙计  全完了
This is bad, man. This is fucking bad, all right?
是吗
Yeah?
要是让他拿到那些箱子
Your law get their hands on them boxes,
老头会杀了我们
that old man gonna kill us!
什么鬼
What the fuck?
现在怎么办
What are we gonna do now?
闭嘴  让我想想
Shut up! Let me think.
你赶紧把剩下的箱子捞起来
You haul ass and pull up the rest of them boxes!
我要把船沉了  处理掉警察
I'm gonna sink this tub and deal with this cop.
你捞完后来接我
You pick me up when you're done.
-老板说  -怎么
- Hey, boss said... - What?
你有什么好主意吗
You got any better ideas?
快去
Go!
快点
Now.
立刻派人去沼泽
We need eyes on the water ASAP.
我们认为苏西·科尔偷偷上了狩猎监督员
We have reason to believe that Susie Coyle may have snuck aboard
-罗比泰尔的船  -收到  警长
- Game Warden Robitelle's boat. - Copy that, Sheriff.
你要和她一起去
You're going out there with her?
怎么了  有问题吗
What, is that a problem?
她当然会先打给你
Of course you were the first person she called.
那是因为她信任我
Well, that's 'cause she trusts me.
你信任你自己吗
Do you trust yourself?
听着  等处理完这个流感
Look, when this whole flu thing is over,
她就会回自己的家去
she's gonna go back to whatever it is she calls home.
-这你很清楚  -我知道她在亚特兰大
- You know that. - Look, I'm well aware
有自己的生活
that she's got a life in Atlanta.
我不知道她在亚特兰大有没有牵挂
Look, I don't know what she's got going on up in Atlanta,
但我知道你已经喜欢她
but I do know that you have been nursing this flame
很长时间了
for a long time.
别说了  妈
Shh... Come on, Ma.
你一旦动情  就很难放下
When you care, you care hard.
你太痴情了  马蒂
There's nothing easy about you, Mattie.
为了你爱的人你可以不要命
You would cut off your right arm for the person you love.
我是你妈  现在我告诉你
And I'm just saying, and this is your mama talking,
和她一起  麻烦少不了
that with this one there, that is a recipe for disaster.
马特
Matt?
小心一点
Just watch yourself out there.
你回来我挺惊讶的
I'm surprised you came back.
一部分是因为疾控中心的决定
Well, the CDC was involved in that decision.
真的吗  多大一部分
Yeah, really? How much?
什么意思
What do you mean?
这个地方有特别之处  我说不好
There's something about this place, I don't know.
想要逃离这个地方  却总会被拉回来
Trying to escape the gravitational pull, people get drawn back in.
我还以为你逃出去了
I thought you made it out, though.
我只是个过客
I'm only passing through.
我想看看我抛下的人过得怎么样
I wanted to see how things were with the people I left.
桑德兰夫妇
Sunderlands.
我得承认  你回来直面他们挺有勇气的
Gotta admit, it's a pretty gutsy choice coming back to face them.
话说回来  体育课上你总是第一个高台跳水的
Then again, you were always the first one off the high dive in gym.
我当年可能就是因为这个才喜欢你
That's probably why I had a crush on you.
拜托  不是说女生都一清二楚吗
Come on, doesn't a girl always know?
我真不知道
I... I had no idea.
所以我在毕业舞会上一直看着你
Yeah, it's why I was staring at you all through prom.
我一直想壮起胆子邀你跳舞
I was just trying to get up the nerve to ask you to dance.
罗比  警长刚给我们打电话了  你在哪儿
Robi, we just got a call from the sheriff. What's your 20.
这下可好
The last fucking thing I need right now.
你在哪儿
Where are you?
你想玩捉迷藏吗
You wanna play hide-and-seek?
你觉得我是在跟你玩吗
You think I'm playing some kind of game?
马特
Matt.
我看到了
Yup, I see it.
天哪  天哪
Oh, my God. Oh, my God.
艾比  小心点
Abby, be careful.
马特  糟了
Matt! Shit.
操
Fuck.
天啊  苏西来过这里
Oh, my God, Susie's been here.
我看到一艘船
I got a boat out here.
操  快去  没事  我待在这里
Fuck. Go, go. It's okay, I'll stay here.
-快去  -你确定吗
- Go. - Are you sure?
她很可能就在那艘船上  马特
Yeah, she could be on that boat, Matt.
快去  把包给我
Go! Give me that bag.
保持联系
Stay in contact.
坚持住  坚持住
Stay with me. Stay with me.
操
Fuck!
对不起
I'm so sorry.
苏西
Susie!
马特  苏西在这里
Matt, Susie's here.
她有危险  赶紧回来
She's in trouble. Please come back.
该死
Shit!
苏西
Susie!
来啊  小混蛋
Come, little fucker.
你可不想跟我玩追逐战
You don't wanna run from me.
你到底是什么鬼东西
What in the fuck are you?
苏西
Susie?
天啊  苏西
Oh, my God. Susie!
苏西  你没事吧
Susie. Are you okay?
天啊
Oh, my God.
苏西  你过...你赶紧过来
Susie, I need you to come... I need you to come down here.
你到我这边来  苏西
I need you to walk to me, Susie.
没事的
It's okay.
快点
Now!
过来  快点  快点
Come here. Hurry, hurry, hurry!
-马特  -艾比
- Matt! - Abby!
玛丽亚
Maria?
该死
Damn it.
凯博  你那边怎么样
Cable, what's your status?
找回科尔家的女儿了  二十分钟后到
Recovered the Coyle girl, ETA 20 minutes.
苏西
Susie.
我们刚刚看到的生物
That creature we just saw...
他很害怕
He's afraid.
他告诉我他不知道自己到底怎么了
He told me he doesn't know what's happening to him.
它和你说话了
It spoke to you?
你记得他还和你说了什么吗
Can you remember anything else he said?
嗯
Yes.
他说他的名字叫亚历克
He said his name was Alec.